so let's see how should we do the
correct out of order execution we should
execute out of order we can broadcast
out of order but we should deposit
values to registers in order this is
needed because if we deposit register
values out of order then if subsequently
we discover that one of the earlier
instruction shouldn't have been done
like it has an exception or it's a
branch misprediction then this
instruction has already deposited it and
it shouldn't have so if we deposit in
order this cannot happen we will
basically deposit results in order so
once we get to deposit that means that
all of the previous instructions have
finished successfully and everything is
fine in tomasulo's algorithm this is not
happening in order this is happening out
of order which is why we have a problem
so what we need is a structure called
reorder buffer even after issue it
remembers the program order and it keeps
the results of instructions until
they're safe to write to registers so
basically instead of writing two
registers whenever the result is
produced it would end up in the reorder
buffer and then we will go in order
through the reorder buffer and deposit
results into the registers and once the
result is deposited to the register only
dead the instruction is considered fully
done